<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Operating System Fundamentals">
  
	<intro>
		<esrtitle>Encrypting Retransmission Device (ERD)</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>National Information Assurance Partnership (NIAP)</maintainer>
		<identifier>42</identifier>
		<version>1.4</version>
		<status>draft</status>
		<issuedate>06 November 2023</issuedate>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
	  This document describes a core set of security requirements for ERD.  
	  These requirements cover basic security behavior for the ERD.  Evaluation 
	  against the resulting PP ensures that this fundamental set of 
	  requirements is met.  These fundamental requirements must be extended to 
	  adequately cover the functionality of many types of applications.
	  <p/>
	  An ERD, in the context of this document, is a boundary device that has 
	  two functions, encrypt traffic between two endpoints and convert traffic 
	  from one network media to another network media while maintaining 
	  isolation from the less trusted network.  This is illustrated in 
	  Figure 1a. The ERD must meet four security properties at the boundary: 
	  confidentiality, isolation, separation and authentication. These will be 
	  referred to as “security”.
	  <figure entity="images/esr_figure1a.png" title="ERD in the overall network" id="1a"/>
	  <p/>
	  A more granular view of an ERD pair is in Figure 1b. An ERD consists of 
	  at least 2 physically separate computing units whose functionality is 
	  Encryption and Communication respectively. They will be referred to as 
	  Encryption Unit (EU) and Communication Unit (CU). An ERD is 
	  cryptographically bonded to another ERD and once bonded they are meant 
	  to only work as a pair to create and manage a point to point encrypted 
	  tunnel between 2 trusted domains over an untrusted domain as 
	  illustrated in Figure 1b.
	  <figure entity="images/esr_figure1b.png" title="ERD granular view" id="1b"/>
	</section>
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
	  This technology has a number of specific use cases (e.g. mitigating 
	  vulnerabilities inherent to commercial wireless technologies, adding a 
	  security layer to SCADA systems, etc.). The basic principle is to 
	  agnostically and transparently interject an encryption operation between 
	  2 endpoints that already communicate without that encryption operation. 
	  For example, a mobile phone and an enterprise VOIP service. Or a 
	  satellite to a ground station. Or a Satellite to Satellite link. An IoT 
	  edge device to a server.
	  <p/>
	  However, in formal Common Criteria evaluations we seek evaluation only 
	  of solutions designed to: 1) replace commercial networking capability 
	  internal to an End User Device (EUD) with an external device (e.g. 
	  Ethernet, LTE, Wi-Fi, etc.) 2) provide an encrypted tunnel to protect 
	  data in transit between EUD’s over said external interface.
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
    	  <ul>
		  	<li>Sensitive data in transit</li>
			<li>Cryptographic key material to perform secure communications</li>
			<li>EU from unauthenticated access</li>
		  </ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Evaluation Boundary" id="evaluationboundary"> 
	  Referencing figure 1b above, the evaluation boundary consists of the 
	  hardware/software within the two ERD modules (ERD 1 and ERD 1’) as well 
	  as the cryptographic link between the modules. More specifically, the 
	  infrastructure to process data entering and leaving EU1 and EU1’ within 
	  the blue dashed box.
	</section>
	
	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
      Functionality-related requirements are:
	  <ul>
	  	<li>The ERD pair must utilize Quantum resistant cryptography.</li>
    	<li>The data pipeline between both sides of the Encryption Unit (EU) must be non-bypassable.</li>
    	<li>The connectivity between the ERD and EUD must utilized wired technology.</li>
    	<li>The communication between the Communication Unit (CU) and EU must be connectionless/stateless.</li>
    	<li>There must be a protocol break between CU and EU.</li>
    	<li>Self-managed between ERD 1 and ERD 1’. Once the initial operating data has been entered, the pair must be capable to manage the key and the link autonomously.</li>
    	<li>The RD pair must implement logging and audit capabilities.</li>
	  </ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
	  <ul>
	  	<li>An attacker is assumed to attempt attacks from the following vantage points:
        	<ul>
				<li>The commercial/wireless network (directly attack the radio on the ERD)</li>
        		<li>The public network the ERD pairs are communicating through</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
    	<li>An attacker is assumed to have the ability to monitor/analyze traffic between ERD pairs as well as monitor wireless signals to/from an ERD.  They are also assumed to have the ability to inject attack vectors through the public network or directly to the ERD radio.</li>
    	<li>The attacker is assumed to be able to gain control of the CU.</li>
    	<li>One ERD of a pair could be stolen or lost.</li>
	  </ul>
	</section>


	<section title="Optional Extensions" id="extensions"> 
	  Encryption unit consists of 2 independent computing units to perform 2 layers of encryption.
	</section>

	<section title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> 
	  There are presently no objective requirements planned.
	</section>

	<section title="Outside the Scope of Evaluation" id="outsidescope">
	  The following list contains items that are explicitly out-of-scope for 
	  any evaluation against the product PP:
	  <ul>
	  	<li>Any network or device connected to interface ‘a’ of the EU (Figure 2b)</li>
		<li>Any network or device connected to interface ‘d’ of the CU (Figure 2b)</li>
	  </ul>
	  <figure entity="images/esr_figure2b.png" title="Enhanced ERD" id="2b"/>
	</section>
	<section title="Additional Note" id="additionalnote">
	  The team is exploring the possibility of making the protocol break (a 
	  version that doesn’t utilize encryption) a selection within the 
	  Protection Profile.  Further discussions are planned between government 
	  stakeholders and industry after the initial formation of the technical 
	  community.
	</section>
</ESR>
